<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Tahoma2D</title><link>https://tahoma2d.org/</link><description>Recent content on Tahoma2D</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 03 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://tahoma2d.org/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Tahoma2D 1.2 is out!</title><link>https://tahoma2d.org/posts/2021/05/03/12release/</link><pubDate>Mon, 03 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://tahoma2d.org/posts/2021/05/03/12release/</guid><description>The latest version of Tahoma2D is now available!
There are quite a number of new features, enhancements and lots of fixes.
You can see what&amp;rsquo;s new here!
Visit the Download page for links to download the latest release. If you have v1.1 or older, be sure to read how to upgrade from prior versions.</description></item><item><title>Tahoma2D 1.2 Beta is now available!</title><link>https://tahoma2d.org/posts/2021/04/19/12beta1/</link><pubDate>Mon, 19 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://tahoma2d.org/posts/2021/04/19/12beta1/</guid><description>Tahoma2D 1.2 Beta includes a number of new features, enhancements and a lot of fixes.
Details in the link below.
A BIG thanks to all those involved from submitting ideas and changes to testing PRs!
Please download the new beta and let us know what you think. You can try it out here!
If you encounter any issues/bugs, please be sure to report it.
Thanks!</description></item><item><title>Tahoma2D 1.1 is out!</title><link>https://tahoma2d.org/posts/2020/10/30/11release/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://tahoma2d.org/posts/2020/10/30/11release/</guid><description>Hi folks!
Thanks so much for using Tahoma2D.
I thrilled to announce that Tahoma2D 1.1 is now available.
Here are some of the things you can expect in the new version:
Over 100 bug fixes, tweaks and new features. Vanishing points and advanced straight line drawing on Vector levels. You can now snap straight lines to 15 degree intervals for greater precision. The vector brush can now draw behind, auto close and auto fill strokes.</description></item><item><title>Tahoma2D 1.1 Beta is now available!</title><link>https://tahoma2d.org/posts/2020/10/16/11beta1/</link><pubDate>Fri, 16 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://tahoma2d.org/posts/2020/10/16/11beta1/</guid><description>Hi folks!
Thanks so much for using Tahoma2D.
I am proud to announce that version 1.1 is now in Beta.
Here are some of the things you can expect in the new version:
91 bug fixes, tweaks and new features. Vanishing points and advanced straight line drawing on Vector levels. You can now snap straight lines to 15 degree intervals for greater precision. The vector brush can now draw behind, auto close and auto fill strokes.</description></item><item><title>Tahoma2D 1.0 is Out!</title><link>https://tahoma2d.org/posts/2020/09/01/1point0/</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://tahoma2d.org/posts/2020/09/01/1point0/</guid><description>Tahoma2D has finally reached a place where I think it is ready for a 1.0 release. Throughout developement, a primary focus is on usability. I think that Tahoma2D has taken many great steps forward in that regard. There are also a bunch of new features to try- including features in OpenToonz that have been added since the 1.4 branch, as well as many features that are exclusive to Tahoma2D.
You can try it out here!</description></item><item><title>What's makes Tahoma2D different?</title><link>https://tahoma2d.org/posts/2020/08/15/switcher/</link><pubDate>Sat, 15 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://tahoma2d.org/posts/2020/08/15/switcher/</guid><description>Coming from OpenToonz? If you are coming to Tahoma2D from OpenToonz, it will feel very familiar. But you will start to notice small changes here and there that help make the experience better.
The list of changes is pretty big. I&amp;rsquo;ll go into more depth about some of these in the future.
UI Updated styles by konero New status bar at the bottom of the program to give hints and tips.</description></item><item><title>Beta 3 is Out!</title><link>https://tahoma2d.org/posts/2020/07/21/beta3/</link><pubDate>Tue, 21 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://tahoma2d.org/posts/2020/07/21/beta3/</guid><description>Beta 3 is out now. Beta 2 accidentally didn&amp;rsquo;t ship with DSLR support, that is back in Beta 3. There are also a few bug fixes. This is also the first beta to have Mac support. Thanks to @artisteacher for all her work in helping out.
Download:
Windows: Tahoma2D Beta 3
MacOS: Tahoma2D Beta 3
The notable new features:
If you are using a Canon DSLR for Stop Motion, the test images now show metadata when you hover over them.</description></item><item><title>First Feature</title><link>https://tahoma2d.org/posts/2020/07/19/fact2/</link><pubDate>Sun, 19 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://tahoma2d.org/posts/2020/07/19/fact2/</guid><description>Fun Fact: The first feature added to Tahoma2D after splitting from OpenToonz was the Test Shots ability in the stop motion panel.</description></item><item><title>Try Beta 2</title><link>https://tahoma2d.org/posts/2020/07/14/beta2/</link><pubDate>Tue, 14 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://tahoma2d.org/posts/2020/07/14/beta2/</guid><description>Beta 2 will launch in the next couple of days. There are a couple of new features and a handful of bug fixes since the last beta.
The notable new features:
If you are using a Canon DSLR for Stop Motion, the test images now show metadata when you hover over them. Eventually I will add the ability to click a button and apply a test shot&amp;rsquo;s metadata to the current camera settings.</description></item><item><title>History</title><link>https://tahoma2d.org/posts/2020/04/16/beginning/</link><pubDate>Thu, 16 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://tahoma2d.org/posts/2020/04/16/beginning/</guid><description>Fun Fact: Work on Tahoma2D began May 16, 2020.</description></item><item><title>About Tahoma2D</title><link>https://tahoma2d.org/about/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://tahoma2d.org/about/</guid><description>Tahoma2D is a powerful program for 2D and stop motion animation. Tahoma2D is based on OpenToonz which itself is based on Toonz, developed by Digital Video in Italy.
The mission of Tahoma2D is to be a powerful and user-friendly animation program for digital 2D artists and stop motion animators.
Tahoma2D is mostly open source, but in order to support Canon cameras, we use the Canon proprietary SDK. Tahoma2D can be built without the SDK, however.</description></item><item><title>Downloads</title><link>https://tahoma2d.org/download/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://tahoma2d.org/download/</guid><description>Windows 64 Bit Portable
System Requirements:
Microsoft Windows 8.1/10 (64bit required) Intel Core i series processor or better 4GB or more RAM 500 MB or more available storage space 1280 x 1024 or higher monitor resolution MacOS 64 Bit Portable
System Requirements:
macOS 10.13 or a later version Intel Core i series processor 4 GB or more RAM 500 MB or more available storage space 1280 x 1024 or higher monitor resolution Linux AppImage</description></item><item><title>Features</title><link>https://tahoma2d.org/features/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://tahoma2d.org/features/</guid><description>Tahoma2D is a full featured program geared at digital and stop motion animation workflows.
It includes:
Powerful drawing engine with support for vector and raster grahics. Support for Canon DSLR cameras and webcams Powerful effects to bring your animation to the next level. Flexible export features to support a variety of formats.</description></item><item><title>Need Help?</title><link>https://tahoma2d.org/support/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://tahoma2d.org/support/</guid><description>Trying to learn how to use Tahoma2D? Checkout the documentation.  Found a bug? Please fill out a bug report.  Wish Tahoma2D could do more? Please create a feature request.  Have another question? Ask a question here.</description></item></channel></rss>